Guide to the Frederick Mortimer Clapp Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Frederick Mortimer Clapp Papers
1852-1969
1906-1969
YCAL MSS 435
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
52.55
(133 boxes)
The Frederick Mortimer Clapp Papers consists of personal and professional correspondence, writings, research material, lecture notes, subject files, diaries, and other papers documenting Clapp's activities as an art historian, educator, and poet as well as his personal and professional relationships. Writings include drafts and proofs for Clapp's various collections of verse and other works such as A History of the 17th Aero Squadron (1920) and The Frick Collection: Paintings: Summary Catalogue (1935). Amongst the extensive lecture notes and research material on various topics are some notes relating to Clapp's research on Pontormo and his work with The Frick Collection. Also found in the collection are the personal and family papers of Clapp's wife, Maud Ede Clapp, which consist of correspondence, diaries, writings and artwork.
Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, 1879-1969
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift and bequest of Frederick Mortimer Clapp, 1966, 1970. Gift of William Q. Maxwell, 1968. Gift of Roger Butterfield, 1971.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Frederick Mortimer Clapp (1879-1969)
Frederick Mortimer Clapp was an American art historian, educator, and poet, and the first director of The Frick Collection from 1936 to 1951. He was born in New York City in 1879, and attended the City College of New York (1896-1899) and then Yale (1899-1902) receiving a B.A. and M.A. He taught at City College and the University of California extension services before traveling throughout Europe and studying art. Clapp married Maud Caroline Ede (1876-1960), an artist in Florence, in 1908. He received a doctorate in art history from the Sorbonne in 1914 and wrote his dissertation on Pontormo's drawings. In 1916 Clapp published a book and catalogue raisonné on Pontormo's paintings. The same year, he began publishing poetry, issuing collections of verse through the 1950s.
Clapp served with the 17th and 22nd Aero Squadrons during the First World War, and wrote a history of the 17th Aero Squadron that was published in 1920. In 1926 Clapp joined the University of Pittsburgh as chair of the art history program. His association with The Frick Collection began in 1931, when he was named advisor to the collection after the death of Mrs. Frick. He became organizing director in 1933, overseeing the transformation of the Frick mansion from a home into the present museum, and then director in 1936, eventually retiring in 1951. Clapp died in 1969 at the age of ninety.
Biographical information drawn from Dictionary of Art Historians:http://www.dictionaryofarthistorians.org/clappf.htm (accessed on 28 January 2011).
Scope and Contents
The Frederick Mortimer Clapp Papers consists of personal and professional correspondence, writings, research material, lecture notes, subject files, diaries, and other papers documenting Clapp's activities as an art historian, educator, and poet as well as his personal and professional relationships. Writings include drafts and proofs for Clapp's various collections of verse and other works such as A History of the 17th Aero Squadron (1920) and The Frick Collection: Paintings: Summary Catalogue (1935). Among the extensive lecture notes and research material on various topics are some notes relating to Clapp's research on Jacopo da Pontormo and his work with The Frick Collection. Also found in the collection are the personal and family papers of Clapp's wife, Maud Ede Clapp, which largely consist of correspondence, diaries, writings and artwork.
Arrangement
Organized into five series: I. Correspondence, 1878-1969. II. Subject Files, 1928-1963. III. Writing and Research Files, 1917-1967. IV. Personal and Other Papers, 1906-1967. V. Maud Ede Clapp Papers, 1852-1960.
American literature -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 20th Century; Art -- History -- Study and teaching; Art historians -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Teachers -- United States -- 20th Century; World War, 1914-1918 -- Regimental histories -- United States; Art historians; Poets; Teachers; Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, 1879-1969; Clapp, Maud Ede; Ede family; Pontormo, Jacopo da, 1494-1556; Frick Collection; United States. Army. Air Service. Aero Squadron, 17th
- Correspondence, 1878-1969; Series I; 17.93; (43 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The bulk of the correspondence was arranged alphabetically by correspondent at a previous point in time by library staff. "To be filed" and miscellaneous correspondence has been left unsorted at the end of the series.
  Scope and Contents
  Letters are to F. M. Clapp unless otherwise noted in the list below.
  Related Archival Materials note
  Miscellaneous letters that had not been previously arranged with the rest of the correspondence can be found in Series IV. Personal and Other Papers.
  - "A" General, 1915-1955; 2 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Peter, 1955-1958 (Box 1)
  - Alden, A. H. to Maud and F. M. Clapp, 1921-1927 (Box 1)
  - Aitken, Webster, 1946-1967 (Box 1)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1967-1968 (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Ian to Maud and F. M. Clapp, 1926-1950 (Box 1)
  - Avinoff, Avery, circa 1928-1949 (Box 1)
  - "B" General, 1911-1967; 2 (Box 1)
  - Barzun, Jacques, undated (Box 1)
  - Bartlett, Alice Hunt, 1939-1948 (Box 1)
  - Beck, L. Adams to Maud Clapp, 1923-1925 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Melba and Frank, 1944-1951 (Box 1)
  - Benson, E. to Maud Clapp, 1904 (Box 1)
  - Bently, Wilder, undated (Box 1)
  - Berenson, Bernard and Mary, 1909-1949 (Box 1)
  - "Bertram", 1925-1947 (Box 1)
  - Bianco, Francesco, undated (Box 1)
  - Biblioteca Nazionale Centrale di Firenze, 1911-1912 (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Margaret, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Bird, Grace Van Dyke, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Birkett, Mary M., 1916 (Box 1)
  - Bisc-cottino to Mr. and Mrs. Clapp, 1920-1922 (Box 1)
  - Bitter, Marie to Maud Clapp, 1931, undated (Box 1)
  - Blanch, Mary S. to Maud Clapp, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Blash, Camilla, 1928-1962 (Box 1)
  - Bouterweck, Helen, 1920-1939 (Box 1)
  - Bouterweck, K. W., 1928-1949 (Box 1)
  - Boughton, Marjorie and Horace, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Browning, Lenore, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Brownson, Carleton L., 1910-1948; 3 (Box 2)
  - Bush, Mary L. to Maud Clapp, 1946-1947 (Box 2)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1926-1968 (Box 2)
  - "C" General, 1909-1952; 3 (Box 2)
  - Chapman, Edward, 1919 (Box 2)
  - "Charlotte", 1950 (Box 2)
  - Christensen, Mildred Ede to Maud and F. M. Clapp, 1946-1948, undated (Box 2)
  - Church, Barbara, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, Maud. Letters from World War I friends, 1914-1916 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, Belle, 1912-1923 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, W. F., Esq., 1914 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, Mrs. W. F., 1911-1914; 2 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, F. M. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1907; 4 (Box 2)
  - Clapp, F. M. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1908-1915; 8 (Box 3)
  - Clapp, F. M. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1915-1918; 10 (Box 4)
  - Clapp, F. M. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1918-1933; 8 (Box 5)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to Belle Clapp, 1911-1935; 2 (Box 5)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to F. M. Clapp, 1907-1909; 8 (Box 6)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to F. M. Clapp., 1910-1915; 10 (Box 7)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to F. M. Clapp, 1915-1918; 8 (Box 8)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to F. M. Clapp, 1918-1932; 9 (Box 9)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to F. M. Clapp, undated (Box 10)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to Mrs. W. F. Clapp, 1912-1914 (Box 10)
  - Clapp Maud Ede to H. G. Dwight, 1914-1923; 10 (Box 10)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to H. G. Dwight, 1923-1931; 10 (Box 11)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to H. G. Dwight, 1931-1935; 8 (Box 12)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to H. G. Dwight, 1935-1950, undated; 10 (Box 13)
  - Clapp, Maud Ede to her father and step-mother, 1898-1899, undated (Box 14)
  - Comings, Marian, 1928 (Box 14)
  - Committee to Defend America, 1941 (Box 14)
  - Comstock, Dorothy, 1925 (Box 14)
  - Culver, A. G., 1949 (Box 14)
  - Cutler & Rooke, 1918 (Box 14)
  - Cutler, Marshall, 1920 (Box 14)
  - "D" General, 1903-1934 (Box 14)
  - Dana, Nathalie, 1926, 1945 (Box 14)
  - Dean, Minni and Jenny to Maud Clapp, 1924-1934 (Box 14)
  - Delius, Frederick, undated (Box 14)
  - de Lune, Pierre, 1916 (Box 14)
  - Del Vasto, Lanza, 1927-1929 (Box 14)
  - "Devi", 1931 (Box 14)
  - Devlin, Denis, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Dickey, Jean (Kellogg) and James, 1909-1966; 3 (Box 14)
  - "Dolly", 1924-1929 (Box 14)
  - d'Udine, Antoinette, 1925-1929 (Box 14)
  - Dwight, H. G. to Maud Clapp, 1904-1906; 3 (Box 14)
  - Dwight, H. G. to Maud Clapp, 1907-1915; 11 (Box 15)
  - Dwight, H. G. to F. M. Clapp and Maud Clapp, 1915-1927; 12 (Box 16)
  - Dwight, H. G. to Maud Clapp, 1928-1933; 8 (Box 17)
  - Dwight, H. G. from F. M. Clapp, 1934-1935; 5 (Box 18)
  - Dwight, H. G. to F. M. Clapp and Maud Clapp, 1936-1957, undated; 7 (Box 19)
  - "E" General, 1909 (Box 19)
  - Eckert, Sam, 1919-1920 (Box 19)
  - "Eddie", 1933 (Box 19)
  - Ede, Charlie to Maud and F. M. Clapp, 1921, undated (Box 19)
  - Ede, Edward H. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1916-1930; 2 (Box 19)
  - Ede, Edward H. to Maud Ede Clapp and F. M. Clapp, 1878-1968; 8 (Box 20)
  - Ede, Helen and Kathleen to Maud Ede Clapp, 1947 (Box 20)
  - Ede, H. S. to Maud Ede Clapp and F. M. Clapp, 1925-1949; 3 (Box 20)
  - Ede, Stanley and "Stig", 1911-1952 (Box 20)
  - Ede family, 1907-1916, undated (Box 20)
  - Edmonds, Lilian, 1949, undated (Box 20)
  - "Elizabeth", 1953 (Box 20)
  - "Ellie", 1915 (Box 20)
  - Esquerre, Helen, 1931 (Box 20)
  - "F" General, 1904 (Box 21)
  - F___, Helen D. to Maud Ede Clapp, 1928-1943, undated (Box 21)
  - Farley, Margaret to Maud Ede Clapp, 1928-1931 (Box 21)
  - Ficke, Gladys, 1953-1956 (Box 21)
  - Ficke, Arthur, 1942 (Box 21)
  - Fisher, Helen, 1942-1949 (Box 21)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1927-1966; 3 (Box 21)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1926-1949, undated (Box 21)
  - Fletcher, Constance, 1905-1921 (Box 21)
  - Fosburgh, James W., 1944-1951; 2 (Box 21)
  - François, P. P., 1911 (Box 21)
  - "Frank", 1942 (Box 21)
  - Frick, Helen Clay, 1931-1967; 4 (Box 21)
  - Frick, Helen Clay, 1931-1967; 2 (Box 22)
  - "G" General, 1909-1951 (Box 22)
  - Garnett, Porter and Edna, 1911-1950; 6 (Box 22)
  - German pictures, 1943-1946; 8 (Box 23)
  - "Gertrude", 1925-1927 (Box 23)
  - Gikes [?], 1912 (Box 23)
  - Gordon, Cora J., 1923 (Box 23)
  - Grampini, Octavio, 1904-1924 (Box 23)
  - Grant, Edward A., 1951 (Box 23)
  - Greenhood, David "Clink", 1926-1969 (Box 23)
  - Griggs, Maitland, 1940-1941 (Box 23)
  - "H" General, 1910-1933 (Box 24)
  - Hague, Marion and Marvin, 1929, undated (Box 24)
  - Hammond, J. Henry, 1936 (Box 24)
  - Harper & Brothers, 1943-1948; 5 (Box 24)
  - Hooker, Katarine to Maud Ede Clapp, 1910-1933; 2 (Box 24)
  - Hooker, Ken to Maud Ede Clapp, 1916-1930 (Box 24)
  - Hooker, M. O., 1928-1930 (Box 24)
  - Hooker, Marion, 1925-1960 (Box 24)
  - Hovey, Walter, 1928-1931 (Box 24)
  - Howard, Marion, 1927-1937 (Box 24)
  - I____, Susan M., 1922-1928 (Box 25)
  - Ilsbury, James M., 1931 (Box 25)
  - "Iris", undated (Box 25)
  - Isley, Samuel M., 1930-1933 (Box 25)
  - J. [?], undated (Box 25)
  - "Janet", 1915-1918 (Box 25)
  - Janson, H. W., 1952 (Box 25)
  - Jeffers, Una and Robinson, 1926-1952, undated; 10 (Box 25)
  - "Jelka", 1909-1915 (Box 25)
  - Jones, Ethel "Bubbles", 1915-1920; 2 (Box 25)
  - Joralnon, Dorothy, 1929-1960; 2 (Box 25)
  - "Josephine", 1910-1929 (Box 25)
  - "K" General, 1949-1964 (Box 26)
  - Kelemen, Elizabeth, 1951-1953 (Box 26)
  - Kelemen, Pal, 1947-1948 (Box 26)
  - "Knelly", 1915-1950; 7 (Box 26)
  - Knox, Helen, 1941 (Box 26)
  - "Kuni", 1949 (Box 26)
  - "L" General, 1915-1967; 4 (Box 26)
  - LaFonciere papers, 1910-1920 (Box 26)
  - Lanzais [?] poem, undated (Box 26)
  - LeRoy, J., 1911-1919 (Box 27)
  - Leuba, Walter, 1929-1969 (Box 27)
  - Levy, William T., 1944-1969 (Box 27)
  - Lewis, Charlton M., 1916 (Box 27)
  - "Lina", 1924-1931 (Box 27)
  - Long, Alice, 1951 (Box 27)
  - Lowell, Amy, 1916 (Box 27)
  - Luhan, Mabel Dodge, undated; 2 (Box 27)
  - "M" General, 1910-1952; 2 (Box 27)
  - M____, Lillie, 1928-1940 (Box 27)
  - MacDonald, Katherine, 1922-1960 (Box 27)
  - McDuffie, Jean, 1926-1931; 2 (Box 27)
  - MacKenzie, H. V., 1906-1929 (Box 27)
  - Magalaner, Marvin, 1944-1952; 2 (Box 27)
  - Magnuson, Beatrice, 1946 (Box 27)
  - "Margherita", 1929-1930 (Box 27)
  - "Marian", 1949-1950 (Box 27)
  - Mariano, Nicky, 1927-1937 (Box 28)
  - Marolle, E., 1924-1930 (Box 28)
  - Marshall, William, Jr., undated (Box 28)
  - Marshall Jones Co., 1917-1929 (Box 28)
  - "Mary", undated (Box 28)
  - Matthias, Blanche, 1938-1949 (Box 28)
  - "Masi", undated (Box 28)
  - Medici Society, 1911 (Box 28)
  - "Mildred", 1933-1952 (Box 28)
  - Monhoff, Fred, 1941 (Box 28)
  - Moore, Dorothea and Earnest, 1909-1941; 2 (Box 28)
  - Morgan, Beatrice and Donald, 1943; 2 (Box 28)
  - Morse, Maud, 1915-1921 (Box 28)
  - Mosgrove, Ellis, 1916 (Box 28)
  - "Muriella", undated (Box 28)
  - "N-O- P" General, 1909-1952; 2 (Box 28)
  - O'Keefe, Georgia, 1945-1960 (Box 29)
  - "Ona" (niece), 1931, undated (Box 29)
  - O'Sullivan, Ellen E., 1957 (Box 29)
  - Ottavio, Gio, 1919-1925 (Box 29)
  - "P" General, 1905-1943 (Box 29)
  - Paderewski Fund, 1949-1951; 2 (Box 29)
  - Patton, Hamish, 1926-1930 (Box 29)
  - Perry, Rachel and Ralph, 1928-1933; 2 (Box 29)
  - Phelps, William Lyon, 1910-1936 (Box 29)
  - Phillips, Marjorie, 1946 (Box 29)
  - Pierce, Molly and Lucy, 1946-1950 (Box 29)
  - "Pittsburgh", 1926-1931; 2 (Box 29)
  - Poggioli, Renato, 1946-1947 (Box 29)
  - Porter, A. Kingsley, 1915-1932; 5 (Box 29)
  - Porter, Bruce and Margaret, 1916-1930 (Box 29)
  - Porter, Lucy, 1919-1931; 6 (Box 30)
  - Pound, Ezra, undated (Box 30)
  - Pucci, Giulia, 1925-1929 (Box 30)
  - Quinn, Henrietta and Cyril, undated (Box 30)
  - "R" General, 1911-1957 (Box 30)
  - R____, D., 1909-1912 (Box 30)
  - Reed, Otis, 1967-1968 (Box 30)
  - Rieber, Henry, 1943, undated (Box 30)
  - Richards, Dorothea, undated (Box 30)
  - Roatta, Ruby, 1927-1947 (Box 30)
  - Robinson, E. A., 1916 (Box 30)
  - Rockefeller, J. D., 1931-1952; 5 (Box 31)
  - Roderick, Virginia, 1918 (Box 31)
  - Rotheram, Ronald, 1947-1967 (Box 31)
  - Rotheram, Wylow, 1909-1942 (Box 31)
  - Royal Society of the Arts, 1950-1951 (Box 31)
  - "S" General, 1889-1965; 2 (Box 31)
  - S____, Muriel, 1921-1938 (Box 31)
  - Sachs, Paul, 1922-1931, 1951; 2 (Box 31)
  - Sachs, Sarton, and 17th Aero Squadron, 1941-1968 (Box 31)
  - Saxton, Eugene, undated (Box 32)
  - "Scoobie", 1942 (Box 32)
  - Scribner's, 1969 (Box 32)
  - Short, Jimsie Porter, 1951 (Box 32)
  - Smyth, S. D., 1915-1920 (Box 32)
  - Solano, Swan & Sweeney, 1959-1960 (Box 32)
  - The Spiral Press, 1957-1960 (Box 32)
  - Stonyhurst, 1950-1951 (Box 32)
  - Sundt, Maud and Peter, 1921-1949 (Box 32)
  - "Suzanette", 1918-1927 (Box 32)
  - Sweeney, Laura and James, 1948-1951; 3 (Box 32)
  - Sullivan, Noel, 1951 (Box 32)
  - "T" General, 1909-1952; 2 (Box 32)
  - Tate, Allen and Caroline, 1950 (Box 32)
  - Thomas, Maude, 1909-1912 (Box 32)
  - Tracy, Henry Chester, 1925 (Box 32)
  - Trollope, Ada, 1930-1933 (Box 32)
  - "Trot", 1921, undated (Box 32)
  - Turner, Katherine S., undated (Box 32)
  - "U-V", 1910-1952; 2 (Box 32)
  - Van Horne, Belle, 1909-1967; 3 (Box 32)
  - Van Horne, G. W., 1968-1969 (Box 32)
  - Van Horne, T. M., 1951, undated (Box 32)
  - "W" General, 1945-1966; 2 (Box 33)
  - Walker, John, 1951 (Box 33)
  - Wallace, Ruth, 1928 (Box 33)
  - Ward, E. J., 1929-1931 (Box 33)
  - Warner, Agnes L., 1916-1952 (Box 33)
  - Webb, Vanderbilt, 1948 (Box 33)
  - Whichello, Mary, 1928, undated (Box 33)
  - Wilkins, Marion, 1914-1942 (Box 33)
  - Williams, Oscar, 1946 (Box 33)
  - Wind, Edgar, 1943-1948 (Box 33)
  - Wotton, Agnes and Susan, 1932-1950 (Box 33)
  - Wygant, Katherine, 1960 (Box 33)
  - "X-Y-Z" General, 1934-1952; 3 (Box 33)
  - Yale University Press, 1919 (Box 33)
  - Youtz, Philip N., 1953-1967 (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous letters, circa 1910-1967; 5 (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous letters, circa 1904-1967; 14 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous / To Be Filed Correspondence
    - "A-Bennett, Melpa", undated; 12 (Box 35)
    - "Bird, Grace - H", circa 1958-1964; 12 (Box 36)
    - "H-Leuba", circa 1958-1964; 12 (Box 37)
    - "L-R", circa 1958-1964; 13 (Box 38)
    - "R-S", undated; 5 (Box 39)
    - "Solita Solano - Z", circa 1958-1964; 15 (Box 40)
    - "Z-Miscellaneous", undated; 13 (Box 41)
    - "Miscellaneous", undated; 10 (Box 42)
    - "Miscellaneous", undated; 16 (Box 43)
- Subject Files, 1928-1963; Series II; 8.55; (21 boxes)
  Files have been left in their existing alphabetical arrangement.
  Titles were transcribed from original folders.
  - Last Will and Testament, 1963 (Box 44)
  - "A" General, 1932-1950; 12 (Box 44)
  - Acquisitions - Sold, 1949 (Box 44)
  - Alfassa, P., 1928-1930; 2 (Box 44)
  - American Type Founders Co., 1929 (Box 44)
  - Applications for Positions, 1932-1939; 3 (Box 44)
  - Art for Sale, 1949 (Box 44)
  - Avinoff, Andrei, Dr. Carnegie Museum, Pittsburgh, 1931-1933; 3 (Box 44)
  - Allied Cause - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies, 1933-1941; 6 (Box 45)
  - Duveen Bros., 1938 (Box 45)
  - Letters about my ancestry F. M.C., 1937 (Box 45)
  - "B" General, 1932-1950; 11 (Box 46)
  - Baker, C. H. Collins, National Gallery, Trefalgar Square, London, England, 1928-1933; 3 (Box 46)
  - Barnow, A. J., Dept. Germanic Languages, Columbia Univ., NY, 1931 (Box 46)
  - Messors J. Batchelor and Sons, Little Chart, Kent, England, 1929-1930 (Box 46)
  - Bibliographical Material, 1934-1935 (Box 46)
  - Binks, Isobel B., Frick Art Ref. Lib. 6 East 71st St. NY, NY, 1930-1933; 2 (Box 46)
  - Books - Drawings in the Fogg Museum, 1941 (Box 47)
  - Books - Drawings of the Venetian Painters, 1944-1945 (Box 47)
  - Bowman, Dr. John G., University of Pittsburgh, 1931-1937; 5 (Box 47)
  - Breck, Joseph, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1930-1932; 2 (Box 47)
  - Broadcast Pageant of Art, 1941 (Box 47)
  - Browning, Lenore, 1934-1935 (Box 47)
  - Brownson, Carleton L., Robert Fulton Hotel 228 West 71st. NY, 1931-1935; 2 (Box 47)
  - "C" General, 1932-1950; 7 (Box 47)
  - "C" General, 1932-1950; 3 (Box 48)
  - Cary, Melbert B., Jr. c/o Morgan and Co. 14 Place Verdme, Paris, 1929 (Box 48)
  - H. W. Caslow and Co. CTD. 82 Chiswell St. London, England, 1929 (Box 48)
  - Caskey, Lacey, 1944-1945 (Box 48)
  - Catalogue of Frick Collection
    - General, 1931-1949; 6 (Box 48)
    - Agreements, 1942 (Box 48)
    - Art News, 1950 (Box 48)
    - Avinoff, Andrei, 1942-1943 (Box 48)
    - Baker, C. H. Collins, 1943 (Box 48)
    - Bowman, John S., 1942-1943 (Box 48)
    - Fogg Museum, 1942-1947; 4 (Box 48)
    - Frick, Helen C., 1942 (Box 48)
    - Ganett, Porter, 1942-1943 (Box 48)
    - Hovey, Walter Read, 1950 (Box 48)
    - Kennedy correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 48)
    - Memoranda, 1942-1943 (Box 48)
    - Notes on Paintings, undated (Box 48)
    - Requests, 1950 (Box 48)
    - Rockefeller, John, Jr., 1942 (Box 48)
    - Sanchez - Canton, 1944-1945 (Box 48)
  - Century Association, 1944-1950; 4 (Box 48)
  - China, Art for, 1941 (Box 49)
  - Clapp, Frederick Mortimer, Dr., 1930-1933; 3 (Box 49)
  - Cole, Joseph G., 1932 (Box 49)
  - College of the City of New York, 1942-1947; 2 (Box 49)
  - College Data, 1934-1935 (Box 49)
  - Committee, Art Acquisitions - Policy, 1939 (Box 49)
  - Committee, Executive, 1949 (Box 49)
  - Conference on Science, Philosophy and Religion, 1940-1942; 3 (Box 49)
  - Constable, W. G., 1931 (Box 49)
  - Continental Typefounders Assn., New York, New York, 1929 (Box 49)
  - "D" General, 1932-1950; 8 (Box 49)
  - Dept. of Fine Arts, 1934-1937
    - Horne, Mildred, 1931-1934; 4 (Box 49)
    - Hovey, Walter Road, 1931-1937; 7 (Box 50)
    - Jarrett, Thomas M., 1931-1935; 4 (Box 50)
    - Lucko, Alma Mary, 1934-1936; 3 (Box 50)
    - Martin, Mercedes, 1936-1937 (Box 50)
    - Programs, 1932 (Box 50)
    - Registration, 1932-1935; 2 (Box 50)
    - Reports, 1931-1937; 4 (Box 51)
    - Resume of Expenditures, 1932-1937; 5 (Box 51)
    - Rupp, G. Stanley, 1931-1937; 7 (Box 51)
    - St. John, Sarah, 1931-1937; 7 (Box 52)
    - Vacation Schedule, 1934-1935 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous, 1934-1944; 4 (Box 52)
  - Duthuit, Georges, 1940-1941 (Box 52)
  - "E" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 53)
  - Edge, Jim, Tate Gallery, 1930-1933 (Box 53)
  - Ede, H. S., 1934-1947; 8 (Box 53)
  - Ede Estate, 1934 (Box 53)
  - Elliot, Philip, 1934-1935 (Box 53)
  - Ely, Alfred, 1932-1935; 6 (Box 53)
  - Enchedé en Zonen, John. Haarlem, Holland, 1929 (Box 54)
  - "F" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 54)
  - Thomas N. Fairbanks Company, 1929 (Box 54)
  - Feipel, Louis N., Director Publications, Brooklyn Public Library, 1930-1935; 4 (Box 54)
  - Forbes, Edward W., Harvard University, 1932-1933 (Box 54)
  - Frick Art Reference Library, 1932 (Box 54)
  - Frick, Helen C., 1928-1943; 8 (Box 54)
  - Gifts to the Frick Collection, 1948-1950 (Box 54)
  - "G" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 54)
  - Garnett, Porter, 1929-1937; 10 (Box 55)
  - Garnett, Porter, 1930 (Box 56)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1948-1950 (Box 56)
  - "H" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 56)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1937-1950; 7 (Box 56)
  - Harrild & Sons, LTD., 1929 (Box 56)
  - Holmes, Charles, 1928-1931 (Box 56)
  - Hoover & Diggs Company, 1932 (Box 56)
  - Hughes, Dr. Wendell L., 1934 (Box 57)
  - "I" General, 1932-1950; 6 (Box 57)
  - Inscription, 1934-1935 (Box 57)
  - International Congress on the History of Art, 1933-1934 (Box 57)
  - "J" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 57)
  - Jeffers, Robinson, 1941-1943; 2 (Box 57)
  - Jury Duty, 1939 (Box 57)
  - "K" General, 1932-1950; 9 (Box 57)
  - Knoedler, M & Co., Inc., 1948-1948 (Box 57)
  - Koechlin, R., 1928 (Box 57)
  - Konte, Robert, 1938 (Box 57)
  - "L" General, 1932-1945; 7 (Box 57)
  - "M" General, 1932-1950; 10 (Box 58)
  - Magnuson, Beatrice A., 1950 (Box 58)
  - Maclagan, Eric, 1931-1935; 3 (Box 58)
  - Macleod, Norman, 1942-1943 (Box 58)
  - Macy, George, 1933 (Box 58)
  - Magnuson, Beatrice A., 1932-1947; 8 (Box 58)
  - Manning, Ethelwyn, 1929-1935; 3 (Box 59)
  - Marquet de Vasselot, J. J., 1929 (Box 59)
  - Mather, Frank Jewett, Princeton University, 1930-1935; 3 (Box 59)
  - Mellon Collection Notes, 1931 (Box 59)
  - Memoranda, 1935-1947; 6 (Box 59)
  - Mills, Adeline L., 1942 (Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous, 1929-1931 (Box 59)
  - Museum Directors - Europe, 1932 (Box 59)
  - "N" General, 1932-1950; 10 (Box 59)
  - National Arts Foundation, 1949-1950 (Box 59)
  - Naughton, W. J., 1931 (Box 59)
  - Nijhoff, W., Jr., 1931 (Box 59)
  - "O" General, 1932-1950; 6 (Box 59)
  - Office - Collection, 1934-1935 (Box 59)
  - Opening - Frick Collection, 1935 (Box 59)
  - Overholt, Karl E., 1928-1937; 6 (Box 60)
  - "P" General, 1932-1950; 10 (Box 60)
  - Paintings from German Museums - Second Resolution, 1948 (Box 60)
  - Office - Pittsburgh, 1931-1933; 3 (Box 60)
  - Porter, Mrs. A. Kingsley, 1934-1936; 2 (Box 61)
  - Porter, Kingsley, 1930-1933; 2 (Box 61)
  - Post, Chandler, 1930 (Box 61)
  - Property of Mr. Clapp in Collection, 1942-1943 (Box 61)
  - Publicity, 1943 (Box 61)
  - Herbert Putnam, Esq. (Librarian), Library of Congress, 1930 (Box 61)
  - "Q" General, 1934-1945; 2 (Box 61)
  - "R" General, 1932-1950; 10 (Box 61)
  - Report of Director to Trustees on the Art Objects in the Frick Collection, 1945 (Box 61)
  - Rockefeller, John D., 1941-1950; 2 (Box 61)
  - "S" General, 1932-1950; 10 (Box 62)
  - Sachs, Paul J., Harvard University, 1928-1947; 6 (Box 62)
  - Sanchez-Cantón, F. J., 1930-1933; 3 (Box 62)
  - Schmidt, Gladys - Poems, 1931 (Box 62)
  - Seligman, J.&W. & Company, 1942-1950; 6 (Box 62)
  - Sieg, L. P., Dean, University of Pittsburgh, 1932 (Box 62)
  - Stout, George L., Fogg Art Museum, 1933-1935; 2 (Box 62)
  - "T" General, 1932-1950; 8 (Box 63)
  - Timme, Walter, 1934-1935 (Box 63)
  - Trustee, New, 1943 (Box 63)